♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ Next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy
named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked
at Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him
into space ♪
♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor
his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make
his robot friends ♪
Robot roll call.
- Cambot.
- Tom Servo: Pan left.
Hi, girl!
What a cool guy!
Wisecracker!
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really
just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
we direct your attention
under the spotlight
to the great
Crow-deenie!
Huzzah!
Lord of unseen forces,
robotic ruler
of the misty
underworld.
And master
of escape.
Yes!
Tonight,
in my most daring
and death-defying
dance with doom,
I will escape from these
cruel and unforgiving
and somehow pleasurable
chains. Oh, my.
Magic Voice:
Commercial sign
in 15 seconds.
Now, Joel, come here
and light the cannon,
point it
at my head.
Don't worry, folks,
he knows what he's doing.
He's the great
Crow-deenie!
Yeah, I saw Telly
do this.
And now--oh, uh, Joel,
can you get that key?
The key is kind of
central to this piece.
- Oh, no.
- ( explosion )
- Whoa!
- Oh, wow.
Bet you're wondering how
I got out of that one?
It's simple, really.
Chewed my head off
just as the cannon
was about to blow.
Neat, huh?
I think
I'm ready to headline.
Don't try this
at home, folks.
Oh, the Great Scout
and Cathouse Thursday
are calling.
In his latest memo,
Mr. Katzenberg said that
he would not tolerate--
- Frank!
- Aah.
Quit sitting around
reading "Variety"
when you should
be working.
But, boss,
check it out.
"The Last Boy Scout" has
dropped out of the top five.
Many of us
in the industry
have taken note
of its lackluster
domestic performance.
I mean, look,
if Bruce Willis' career
continues its downward slide,
it could be a setback to
the forces of evil everywhere.
You're right, Frank.
This is cause for concern.
Remember
"The Return of Bruno"?
- Ahh.
Well, let's skate on
to this week's
invention exchange.
Get on with it,
Joel.
First came
the instant camera.
Then came
the instant cash machine.
I say, do what I do.
Put them together.
And now you can put
anybody's kisser
on any U.S. currency.
Gypsy, say
"Richard Basehart."
Richard Basehart.
See? It's called
the Dollar-oid.
Check it out.
And now we've got
a special presentation
by Sir Crow T. Robot
and Dame Tom Servo
on some of the merits
of the Dollar-oid.
( clearing throats )
Excuse me,
Mrs. Retail Lady person.
- I would like--
- Yes?
I would like to purchase
one of your fine products
using this $5.00 bill.
Well, sir, if I'm going
to take that $5.00 bill,
I'm going to need some
proper identification.
No problem. My picture's
right here on the bill,
so you can cash my fiver
with a clear conscience.
- How was that?
- Oh, how convenient.
Now all I have
to do--
Wait a minute.
Joel, get in here.
What's going on?
You don't need
identification
for cash money.
This whole concept
is absurd.
Here's a little
hush money.
Don't tell your mother
I gave you this, all right?
Hush money?
Wait, wait, this money
has my picture on it.
It's totally worthless.
You could never
use money like this.
What is this,
some kind of joke?
Am I some kind of clown?
Do I amuse you
in some fashion?
- Why do you think, sirs?
- It's absurd if the--
Your invention is absurd.
It's ridiculous.
It makes absolutely
no sense whatsoever.
I love it.
Keep up the good work.
Oh, shut up, Frank.
Well, Mariette Hartley,
our invention exchange
this week
deals with the concept
of facial tissue.
We've come up with
tissue that has faces.
That's right.
Think right-wing
columnist Pat Buchanan
is no one to sneeze at?
Well, now you can.
Frank's chosen
the Kleenex line
of Presidential
candidates for '92,
while I've relied
on the "Star Search"
comedy competition
runners-up series.
For instance,
there's Sinbad.
Ah...ah...
Women be different
than men--Ah-choo!
Or there's
Rick Ducommun.
I hate...ah-choo!
And what collection
would be complete
without 10-time winner
Geechy Guy?
I lost to a damn
ventriloquist! Ah-choo!
You know, I'm having
a hard time sneezing
into this thing.
I mean, maybe Pat Buchanan
really is no one to sneeze at.
He's even more evil
than Bruce Willis.
Some fresh pepper,
Frank?
Yeah. Ah...ah...ah-choo!
Ah-choo! Ah-choo!
Oh, no! Frank's sneezes
are in Sensurround.
Frank, no!
Ah...ah...ah...oh.
Your experiment
this week, Joel,
is called
"Space Travelers."
It's actually "Marooned"
with the Film Ventures
International treatment.
A new credit sequence,
in other words.
And the presence
of Gregory Peck
or Gene Hackman
does not diminish
the pain in any way.
Frank, push the bu--
No, Frank, no!
Ah...oh.
Ah-choo! Ah-choo!
Ah-choo!
Absolutely ridiculous.
You can see the whole--
- ( alarm )
- We've got movie sign!
Hey, it's
the big blue marble
brought to you
by the unpainted place.
Oh, that's strange.
Produced by me,
Al Frankovich.
That's good.
We're in it now
up to our necks.
Or pecks.
Oh, Richard Crenna.
Lukey from
"The Real McCoys."
Dagnabbit, Lukey.
Ah, the one-armed man
is chasing me.
I need a drink.
Oh, James Franciscus.
Wasn't he
in "The Finder
of Lost Loves?"
No, no, that's
Tony Franciosa.
This is star-studded,
isn't it?
Wow.
Oh, Gene Hackman.
He's good in anything,
you guys, really.
Yeah, he's really good.
Call Space Travelers.
We're able to book
any vacation.
Oh, I get it.
It's a cable access
version of "Marooned."
Yeah.
Mariette Hartley.
She's got two navels,
you know.
I wonder
if she's gonna be
in "Genesis Two:
The Next Generation."
Oh.
Never been
in anything.
Vince, oh--
Oh, it could
be worse.
Vince Van Patten
could've been in this.
You know, when this was made,
Vince was just a gleam
on his father's forehead.
Lyle Wheeler from the
production design team
of Wheeler
and Woolsey.
Oh, and Walter
"Big Train" Thompson.
Like father,
like son.
Think about it,
won't you?
Frightening,
isn't it?
Boy, I could go
for some Fapp-jacks
drizzled with butter
right about now.
Mm-hmm.
Fapp-jacks.
Mayo Simon.
Is he related to
Lillian Hellman?
Lillian Hellman
sandwich bread
has alcohol and
cigarette butts in it.
Come to M.J. Frankovich's
for imported Polish sausages.
John,
you've done better.
I'll say.
John Tesh
at the keyboards.
( humming )
So let the carnage begin.
Here at
Phillips Petroleum,
we've found ways to replace
the environment.
Take, for example, these
plastic self-cleaning ducks.
( quacks )
Here are trees
being assembled,
workers replace clouds.
Pressurize
all of the tanks
in all three stages
with gaseous helium.
As the pressurization
builds up,
it's being monitored--
This used to be a wetlands
preserve in North Dakota.
Well, we've shellacked it
and covered it
with an acrylic polymer.
You can take it
to the terminal count.
Roger, Flight,
we are go.
Okay. Let's check status
with the terminal count.
You think this is
one of those CB movies
from the '70s?
Pigpen, this is
Rubber Duck.
I'm gonna put
the hammer down.
Quiet,
Ratchet Jaw.
Go, all the way.
Panel Three.
Tape recorder forward.
Switch to forward.
Verify gray bar.
- Roger, we have--
- Wow is this cool!
Roger, automatic sequence.
Start on my mark.
Roger, make sure
you don't put it
in reverse.
All right, Jim, stand by
your panel 325 function.
- Roger.
- Fuel 3 pressure initiated.
Roger, fuel. This one's
gonna light on your toes.
PCS bypass on.
You know, Mark and Roger
do a good job
down at the plant.
Oh, yeah.
They do
a super job.
This is launch control.
The second stage--
That's pre-pay
after dark, sir.
Lift the handle, sir.
Lift the handle.
Looks like they're
cutting out the nose-cone
to spite the rocket.
Loud and clear, Dick.
All right.
CMP on panel 2.
Verify program 2.
We're go, Flight.
All right, guys,
why don't you solve
your little problems
and light this candle?
Yeah, light the candle.
All recorders
to flight speed.
Sounds like they can't get
their VCR programmed either.
RTC, you got everybody
configured for commands?
That's affirmative.
Internal power and go,
Flight.
Oh, it's the three stooges
from "It's a Mad, Mad,
Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World."
Standby
for the 10 second count.
Roger, Ted.
Okay, everybody
gone potty?
10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, ignition.
Guess we know what's
coming, don't we?
I meant to say clear
the launch pad. Sorry.
( laughs )
Watch out
for the back draft.
Hey, and it takes off, too. Wow.
Wait, that's
the ST-Saturn-V.
That's a level 5,
you know?
Oh, yeah,
tumble recovery.
( chanting )
You know, this movie works
because we care
about the characters.
Yeah, I do.
- Charles Rocket.
- D'oh!
You know, $8 million film
and they're still using
stock footage! Jeez.
( imitating Kennedy)
Before this decade
is out,
we will make
a boring movie
called
"Space Travelers."
Oh, yes. Yes, yes.
- Bye.
- Pretty.
Hey, The Residents.
Yep.
- Booster okay?
- Go, Flight.
Go, Flight.
Well, actually,
this is more like
the level of the Mars
Snooper level three.
Yeah, it takes 3 Ds.
Yeah. Oh, you're thinking
of the Cherokee, dude.
That had the trunk
cover recovery.
Take it or leave it,
Flight. We're go.
Oops, that was me.
Sorry.
Oh, come on.
- Seen it. Yeah.
- Seen it. Yeah. Taped it.
A few times.
I thought I told you to
check that trailer hitch.
( laughs )
Three boys
in plastic bubbles.
Yeah, but look
at that acting.
Hackman
is always good.
- Mm-hmm.
- He's good.
Take it out of first,
will you?
There you go.
Thank you.
Looks like Pac-Man.
The tower
has jettisoned.
Trajectory and guidance
are a go.
Joel, what is the big deal?
It's three men in space,
wearing helmets
that afford them a certain
amount of protection.
Well, I think the point
they've established so far
is that they're
going into space.
I think that's
probably established.
Maybe we'll need another
10 minutes or so
to make it clear.
I've seen that, too.
I hope they
didn't need that.
- Yep.
- Spacecraft systems are go.
Spacecraft systems
are go.
All spacecraft systems
So are all
spacecraft systems go?
I'm getting that idea.
- We have CECO.
- Roger, CECO.
Seka, on the ship?
Buck-a-wow.
♪ Sitting
around the lake ♪
♪ Mountains come out
of the sky and-- ♪
♪ Doom, doom ♪
Say no to Yes.
Hey, look, they're wearing
jockstraps on their heads.
- ( all laugh )
- Goofy.
Hey, check it out.
Space capsule's
got a red butt.
- Whoo-hoo.
Pop-o-matic
pops the dice.
I am Iron Man.
Hey, you can see Aaron
Spelling's house from here.
Well, he worked
for Aaron Spelling
when he starred on
"Finder of Lost Loves."
No, no, no, that was
Tony Franciosa.
Hey, looks like
a fine day down there.
Hey-hey.
I can see all the way
from Gibraltar to Greece.
I'm a highly trained
professional
and it's still cool.
Should be our first sunset
in a couple of minutes.
Check it out. I'm giving
Houston the finger.
Loss of signal
with Canary.
( applauding )
You know, he's always
good, isn't he?
Activate
TV transmission.
No TV till
you do your homework.
We remote to Houston
through Araya, Buzz.
Araya One, this is Ironman.
How do you copy? Over.
On a Xerox machine. You?
Araya, I read you
loud and clear. Copy.
I read you the same.
On my mark, TV transmission
from camera A.
Mark.
Hey, it looks like
Value Vision.
We're huge. Over.
How are you getting this?
A little snowy,
Ironman.
A little snowy.
There we go.
( mumbles )
Eh, just a little
Harry O. of the dog
that bit me.
Clear now.
Good picture.
Well, say something, Ted.
Are we beautiful?
Do you think we're sexy?
Ironman,
this is Houston.
I'm sorry, I was
watching "Gidget."
Could you repeat
that last remark?
This material was obtained
during their first week
in space.
I'm presenting it
as a point of reference.
- Here's Pruett.
- Exhibit A.
Lloyd.
Stone.
He's a blast,
that dude. He's good.
We got this
day before yesterday.
Now look at this idiot.
Poor bastard thinks
he's a spaceman.
( laughs )
It demonstrates
a serious decline
in the ability to perform
even simple manual tasks.
Like grinding coffee,
as we see here.
Just over five months
of the mission
have been completed
satisfactorily.
We wonder if it
remains desirable
to continue
for the full seven months
originally planned.
Look here. This
is where he wets them.
Sad, really.
Oh, boy.
What are your parameters,
Courtney?
Well, let's just say
I cover the waterfront.
EKG, rate and rhythm.
EEG, brain.
- E.G. Marshall.
- He's not sleeping.
E.G. Marshall?
The trend shows
definite fatigue.
Is he still
losing weight?
Another Jenny Craig
success story!
The quality of the
solar spectral film's
been very poor.
Well, you're not
gonna see any more.
Why not?
Gets pretty weird
after this.
Take a look at this.
It'll make you sweat.
Oh, boy.
Millions of dollars spent
on this space program
and no one thought
of camera straps.
It's the little things,
really.
He's tired and he's
making mistakes.
You wanna try
living in a tin can
for five months?
Hey, I lived in an efficiency
in Manhattan, you know.
- What else?
- We got this yesterday.
They're putting on
a production of "Our Town."
Sad, really.
Some further degradation
to our CS system.
We've lost a backup coolant
loop in the oil thruster.
Man, Hackman's
really good in this.
Yeah.
The washing machine is out.
I was doing
some preventative
maintenance on it
and I guess
I shorted it out.
I also discovered
some computation errors
in the telescope settings.
I guess that accounts
for the poor quality
in the solar
spectral pictures.
- What, what, what?
- I don't know.
Oh, oh.
I broke some
other stuff, too.
I made this thing
out of clay.
I think it's a duck.
I fixed the razor.
I'll send you a bill
for that.
( laughs )
So we can go back
to shaving again now.
( laughs )
I resent that.
I'm sleeping better.
He's high.
I guess we're all
getting our second wind.
Yeah, we can smell it
down here.
If the hardware holds up,
I guess we can
make it right to the end.
I know I can.
I can.
For headache pain,
they need Excedrin.
Bring them down.
Yes, sir.
Honey, the meeting's over.
You were right. We're
gonna bring them down.
You're always right.
Get everyone on that
in mission control.
Well, you know,
Gene Hackman's even good
in this scene.
Yeah, James Franciscus
even better in this
than he was in
"Find Our Lost Loves."
Crow, that was
Tony Franciosa!
Ahh.
Music by Tangerine Dream.
Sounds like Tomita.
I don't know,
it kind of sounds like
that Irish chanteuse Enya.
No, it sounds like
the last chord
in "A Day In the Life,"
only they slowed it
way down.
It's a little like
Wendy Carlos, so...
This is mission control
Houston.
The crew of Ironman One
has closed down the S-4B
space laboratory
in which they have
worked, lived,
slept and eaten for
the last five months.
It's like a golf
tournament.
Their Apollo spacecraft
has separated from the
lab and at this time,
the automatic sequence
of retrofire
is about to begin.
10, 9, 8...
Call in now
with your pledge
and you'll get
this great tote bag.
4, 3, 2, 1.
Thanks,
frick and frack.
Retrofire.
The spacecraft should be
starting its descent
across Australia
towards the splash point
in the Pacific,
some 400 miles south
of Midway Island.
Jeez, he's
patronizing, isn't he?
We're waiting now
for confirmation
of retrofire.
Standing by for contact.
Ironman One, Ironman One,
this is Houston CapCom.
Do you read?
Punky Brewster's dad,
the early years.
Ironman One,
Ironman One.
This is Houston.
CapCom, do you read?
Crummy Madonna
microphones.
After five months
in orbit,
a mission
that has been termed
a successful prelude
to the long-term
space voyages
that someday will be
normal and routine.
So how come forehead here
gets all the dialogue?
Astronauts Jim Pruett,
Buzz Lloyd and Clayton Stone
should be on
their fiery way home
to the good Earth.
Ah, don't say fiery.
Ironman One, Ironman One.
This is Houston CapCom.
Do you read?
Come on, answer
so I can make happy hour.
Ironman One,
Ironman One.
This is Houston CapCom.
Do you read?
Ironman One,
Ironman One.
- It's monkey bars.
- Hmm.
Now come along with us
as we take a visual tour
of the radio signal.
You see, radio
is an electric impulse
that travels through--
- ( high pitched beeping )
- What? What? What? What?
Ironman One,
Ironman One.
- It's okay.
- Are they calling us?
Go ahead, Houston.
Hey, you old bum,
how's the run?
We have negative retrofire.
Oh, we finally got
a plot point, guys.
- Whoo!
- Say again, Ironman.
Negative. No burn.
Bailey, kill it.
- Ironman, wait one.
- What's wrong, Dick?
- What'd you call me?
- I don't know.
E-COM, GNC,
how does the data look?
It looks fabulous!
A minute and seconds
past retrofire.
Ironman, Flight.
Would you check your
pilot circuit breakers
and also your
Delta V thrust manual
A and B switches?
- Roger.
- You getting any of this?
Glenn, would you
punch up channel six?
And could you
punch me in the gut?
All parameters are normal.
Uh-oh.
Why in the hell
doesn't it fire?
- Houston, Ironman.
- Now they're in trouble.
Go, Ironman.
Circuit breakers are
closed, SPS switch is on.
Oh, here your script
changes, Mr. Peck.
Delta V manual A and B
switches are on.
Thank you, Ironman.
We're affirming
a new target.
Suggest you try
manual re-entry
on your next pass.
Roger. Understand.
Manual re-entry
using
RCS backup system.
Negative, Jim. Negative.
Are you positive?
Suggest you use
the primary system.
That is smart.
Gee, guess that's why
we're up here.
We just told them
the thing didn't work.
Houston, we prefer using
the backup thrusters.
Nope. No, no, no.
I'm afraid
you don't have
any backup thrusters.
Say again?
I said, nice weather
we're having. ( laughs )
What about the lab?
There's oxygen in the lab.
Houston, do we have
enough fuel
to re-dock with the lab?
Oh, here, say this
right there.
- Negative, Ironman. Negative.
- Good, good.
Well, what do you
propose, Ted?
You have
insufficient RCS fuel.
You're going
to have to try retrofire
with your primary
engine.
Well, it makes sense.
Everything's retro
these days.
Smart boys think
your automatic
control system is out,
but you'll be able
to get ignition
from your primary engine
on manual command.
Now, remember, pump it first,
but don't flood it.
In other words,
kick the box, Jimmy.
Do you copy, Ironman?
Your jockstrap will double
as a floatation device.
Yeah, copy.
Mr. Keith, BAO.
Yeah, no announcement.
I think we should say
something, sir.
We've been off the air
now for almost--
All right.
Just keep it trivial.
Keep it routine.
- We may not have a problem.
- Yes, sir.
This is mission control
Houston.
We're all gonna die!
We received word
from Ironman One
of a malfunctioning
switch
that has
prevented retrofire
on their last orbit.
They'll bypass
the switch...
Oh, high tech, my butt.
They don't even have
touchtone phones. Oh.
If I'm not mistaken,
that's Newt Gingrich.
- This is Canon in Houston.
- Yeah, Canon?
Well, unfreeze the dead,
will you?
- Hold on a second.
- Huh?
- Are you ready now?
- Go ahead.
Open wide.
The primary engine did not
fire on the first pass.
The secondary thrusters
are out. Repeat, out.
The party
of the first part,
who in this part
shall be known as the--
If that big baby
doesn't fire this time,
they're not coming back.
Motor, pitch two
and yaw two start, on.
Pitch two and yaw two
start, on.
- One minute to burn.
- One minute to burn. Roger.
Translation hand
controller, neutral.
- Neutral.
- Hand controller neutral.
Hand controller power,
both.
- Career to off.
- On.
Direct RCS, on.
Direct RCS.
Delta V thrust,
A and B normal.
You see that?
- That's a Yahtzee.
- 30 seconds to burn.
30 seconds. Roger.
Hand controller's armed.
You know it's neat
how they all have
their own little tasks,
you know.
That's so creative.
Hand controller's
are armed.
EMS Delta V, auto.
Word up.
Delta V, auto.
15 seconds to burn.
Roger, 15 seconds.
Acknowledge.
All right, you bastard,
fire, fire, fire!
Hey, whoa, easy, easy.
Get him something.
10, 9, 8, 7, 6...
Whoa, we better go, guys.
4, 3, 2, 1, retrofire.
You know,
the American space race
has contributed
a whole lot more
than just a lot of grainy
black and white photos
to the great American way.
Yes, science, technology,
and processed foods
were advanced
beyond the reckoning
of our puny little minds.
It has been said
that one cannot swing
one's dead cat
without hitting an item
that has been advanced
by the space program.
We begin. The vitamin pill,
a space race advancement.
Frozen dough.
Thank you, NASA.
The tie clip.
Keep it going now.
- The coffee table.
- Spats.
- Chia technology.
- Tin whistles.
- The nylon windbreaker.
- Naugahyde.
Swirled yogurt,
essential for space flight.
- Battered fish sticks.
- The collapsible top hat.
The thing maker.
Helicopters, planes,
and ordinary table salt.
Scooby-doo
and Scrappy-doo.
Branford, Wynton,
and chicken Marsalis.
The meatball--
100% space technology.
The Styrofoam peanut,
the circus peanut,
and the Woozle
whose name was Peanut.
- The bendy straw.
- Jim Mitchum.
- The Basset Hound.
- Scattergories.
"Policewoman,"
the TV show.
Margarine.
You see, the space race
has contributed
so much to our lives
that we really couldn't
even understand it all.
All we know
is that it's friendly
and it's good for us
and we need it
really, really a lot.
So open your hearts and
open your wallets and give.
Think about it, won't you?
Thank you.
- Bikini waxing.
- White corpuscles.
The Swedish steam cooker.
What about mumbley-peg?
- Oh, Kate Bush.
- Beef pinwheels.
Polident?
- Ooooh...
Strawberry cereal cubes.
Oh, look, quisp and some
tenderloin in béarnaise sauce.
Breast implants.
Jim, why are we just lying
here waiting, huh?
For Ground to analyze
the entire telemetry.
So some smart-ass engineer
can tell us
we're out of luck?
"So some smart-ass engineer
can tell us
we're out of luck?"
Why not go EVA? We'll
check the engine ourselves.
Maybe one of the fuel valves
is frozen.
Oh, come on, get real.
No, Ground
could tell that.
Maybe we took
a meteor strike.
Maybe something hung up
on separation.
Eew, this is
Bob's filth.
Just relax. Eat your
chicken while it's hot.
Wait a minute.
What are you
looking at, Stoney?
The smog coming in
over L.A.
It'll burn off
by noon.
That disturbance in the inner
tropical conversion zone.
Somebody's gonna have
a hurricane.
- Subplot. Subplot.
Subplot. Subplot.
Oh, it's just
northeast of Cuba.
They call it Mariah.
Uranus test, I believe.
Yeah, nice thick clouds.
Good east-west slope.
Cyclonic circulation
just beginning.
Yeah, she's
gonna be a big beast.
Oh, don't tease me.
You're making me hot.
Alma. First of the season.
Oh, baby.
Just eat the chicken.
Don't play with your food!
Now you're bugging me.
Open it!
Would you just eat
your chicken, please!
Houston, this is Simulator.
We have on the stand
SPS engine,
unit H37,
modified block four.
This unit is an exact
one-to-one duplicate
of the primary equipment
in Ironman One.
Uh, this call
for any of you guys?
And we're attempting
to construct a configuration
which will reproduce
the conditions
that prevented ignition.
David Doyle,
the early years.
3, 2, 1...
Thunderbirds are go!
I say, apparently
we have failed
to prevent ignition,
but we'll keep
working on it.
- I'll say.
- Fire him.
I will be back
in "MacKenna's Gold."
( hum theme from
"MacKenna's Gold )
The President's waiting
for our recommendations.
One, a statement
to be issued
at the conclusion
of this meeting:
Every effort
is being made
to discover and correct
the spacecraft
malfunction...
There's a guy named
Earl working on it.
With contingency plans
designed to meet
such emergencies.
Boy, I hate my job.
Two, a report to be
issued Tuesday morning
by the director
of manned space flight,
emphasizing the high
degree of safety...
I could really go
for a scotch.
In the program thus far.
The accident
will be compared
to the failure of an
experimental aircraft.
Nice. Good analogy.
We noted that
in the development
of such aircraft,
a 10% pilot loss...
How come he gets to sit
in the big chair?
Now, Wednesday morning,
if necessary...
3 AM.
The President will issue
an appropriate message...
Then he'll vomit on
some Japanese people.
- Emphasizing the courage...
- Yeah, I did.
And determination
of the crew.
♪ The Minnow
would be lost ♪
And their final wish,
that the program be
continued without pause.
Oh, nuts, now
I've lost my place.
Discussion?
( hiccups )
Excuse me.
Yeah, I have something.
Yes, you hurt me earlier.
I want to talk about
a rescue mission.
In my underwear.
I'm speaking
for the pilots and some
of the Air Force boys.
For the laughter, for
the love, for the boys.
We propose launching
a rescue craft
using one of their
boosters.
He is plucky.
He is.
Dougherty, you haven't
been listening.
Courtney, will you repeat
that trend data
on oxygen consumption
in the spacecraft?
As of now,
they're going to live
another 42 hours,
plus or minus 2%.
Oh, man,
am I hung over.
Now, that takes us up
to 10:30 Monday night.
There's a launch
window for a shot
at 8:48 Monday night.
I don't wanna. No.
An Air Force Titan
3C corp
left Denver for the Cape
one hour ago.
Oh, actually, it was
already in the pipe.
And also the XRV lifting
body from Edwards.
Can you get
the Titan and an XRV
on the pad, ready to go,
in 42 hours?
Some of our boys
think they could.
A non-man-rated booster
and a craft
that's never flown.
Oh, it'll fly all right,
and Dougherty here has
all the qualifications.
No, no, no, no.
Proposal is rejected.
Anything else?
Well, we could have
a fundraising carnival.
Yeah, what do I tell
the pilots?
Tell them that the request
is outside the area
of their competence.
Oh, you mean
they're too dumb?
We've got three men
up there dying.
They're professionals.
If they were here now,
they'd say take
what you've learned
and get on with
the next mission.
I don't give a damn
about the next mission!
Dougherty, there's no room
in this program
for a chief astronaut
who cannot look
at the whole picture.
Then fire me.
Sober up and then
we'll talk about it.
You want to launch
a rescue mission
in 42 hours. All right.
So they can't
get back to Earth.
Is that
what they're saying?
Stage one, stage two
and trans stage.
How long, Colonel,
on past performance?
On past performance,
12 days, but if we were--
12 days.
Two, build up and strap on
solid fuel stacks.
Four days, but we can--
- Four days.
- Third base.
Check out launch weather
for Monday night.
There's a hurricane
out there.
600 miles off the coast
and headed out to sea.
Well, you're in luck.
Three, make the vehicle
to the bird
and check out configuration.
How long, Colonel?
Duh, I left my notes
at home.
Sorry, so much.
Couldn't do it
under five days.
Four, compute navigation
and guidance tapes
for first
apogee rendezvous.
10 days.
Program computers.
So what's
your point?
Three weeks.
We'll go without a computer.
We'll go without a checkup.
And crew training
in a craft
which has not been
man-rated,
which cannot be flown
by one pilot
and which has not
been modified
to hold four men.
Hey, wake up.
How about that one?
Scorched you, huh?
Face.
We'll do it in 42 hours.
Or my name isn't
Harry O., U.S. Treasury!
While you're assembling
your rescue ship in 42 hours
and spending--well, how much
would that cost, Fisher?
50 million.
- So what?
- Plus how many deaths?
Three, sir. Maybe.
In a program
of this magnitude,
in which all nominal safety
factors are disregarded,
I calculate .02%
of the workforce will--
Just how in the hell
do you know how many
people are gonna die?
You think we haven't
considered rescue?
Here it is.
Rescue and every other
contingency.
Here it is.
Reduced to digitals
and computerized.
There's Bill Shatner's
report, right here.
You helped to write it.
A rational approach.
Well, screw your
rational approach.
Yeah, well, bite me,
Harry O.
Three of your pilots
are in trouble,
and if you don't
try to get them down,
well, goddamn you!
Whoa!
You got me.
That was fair.
Well, you have feelings.
Good. I have feelings.
That's why
we live by the rules.
Ape law.
- Wheeler.
- Woolsey.
- Courtney. Fisher.
- Price.
- Klein. Degrote.
- Calvin.
We've got a bingo.
Those men up there
are your friends.
Can you launch a rescue
mission in 42 hours?
You bet we can.
We'll get a barn
and I'll paint the sets.
We'll put on a rescue mission
that'll take it us
straight to Broadway!
( buzzer )
Time's up.
How much did you risk?
All of it? I'm sorry.
It's Commissioner Gordon.
Yeah, we're ready
at this end.
- Uh-huh.
- Very good.
The girls are here.
The President
will take the call
at 7:00 his time.
Ironman One,
this is Houston Flight.
Go, Houston.
We're coming up
to get you, Ironman.
- We've called AAA.
- Say again?
We're coming up
to get you.
That's what
I thought he said.
We're launching a rescue
mission from the Cape.
Hey, it's helmet day
at NASA.
David Janssen wishes
it was beer day.
Modified to hold four men.
Now, there are men
without hats.
Oh.
Do you read, Ironman?
Yeah, we read you.
Yeah, whatever.
Houston, when do you
estimate launch?
Just over 40 hours,
Stoney.
40 hours?
Who are they kidding?
Do you read, Ironman?
No, but I read "Final Exit,"
and it's gonna come in handy.
We've decided to make
a move up here.
Go EVA and eyeball
the engines.
The fuel valves
could be frozen.
We'll pull
the insulating hatches.
If they are,
when we get in the sun,
we'll try and get
some heat on 'em.
That's an interesting
thought, Ironman,
but we have no indication
of that here
or anything else
you could correct.
We're all agreed
the rescue mission is it.
Well, we're
all agreed here
that we have to take
some affirmative action
to repair our vehicle.
Well, we're gonna hire
some women and minorities.
Ironman, standby one.
Tell them negative,
Jimmy, negative.
Always with
the negative waves.
Jim, we appreciate
your desire to take
affirmative action
and we need your
if the mission
is to succeed.
But shut up!
The most critical factor
is your oxygen supply.
You get 15 minutes
of activity outside
the spacecraft
to eyeball the engine,
you're going to have
to trade off
three or four hours
of passive breathing.
Hmm.
From where we sit,
you don't have
that oxygen to spare.
Well, what's your Malibu
Barbie watch say there?
Therefore,
we'd like to suggest
that you go
into low-tide mode,
lower your
oxygen pressure to 3.5,
execute a full
emergency power down
and take your pills.
Hey!
They want us to buy it
while we're sleeping.
We got Judy Garland
on the line.
She'll be advising you
on the pill thing.
Do you copy, Ironman?
- What? Oh.
- Yeah.
We're thinking about it.
Not!
Tell them negative, Jim,
negative.
- Pruett.
- Is this thing on?
Now this is Keith.
I'm down here at
the Cape with Sadler.
I'm doing karaoke.
And we're getting this
rescue shot ready to go.
Now, don't do
anything foolish.
Don't climb into
your hard suits.
Don't get out your tools and
don't try to fix the engine.
Don't sleep in
the subways, baby.
Just take your pills
and go to sleep.
And don't eat
refrozen ice cream
and don't mix
household cleaners.
We've got a better chance
than you do, Jim.
- ( all laugh )
- We'll be back at you.
Buzz, you eat up
25% more oxygen
every time
you lose your cool.
What's a four letter word
for fiery death?
Houston, Ironman.
Please pull ahead
to the first window.
- Preparing for power down.
- Roger, Ironman.
Hmm.
What are the numbers,
Stoney?
Cleveland 8,
Cincinnati 4. Uh-oh.
Well, with nominal
oxygen usage,
that'll make it
36 hours left.
Uh-huh.
Take out the pad,
40 hours, more or less.
I've got sleep apnea,
so I won't use up much.
How you figuring
the residual amounts
in the tanks?
( laughs )
How would you?
Gene! Gene!
He just
doesn't care.
Yeah, you'd have to breathe
them dry to find out.
No one's
ever done that.
Well, I got the feeling
we just may be the first.
Oh, look, they're doing
the Hindu rope trick.
Whoo.
( sirens )
From "Marooned"
to Gator McKlusky.
( laughs )
We now return
to "Cannonball Run."
( all humming )
So I guess
the point here is,
that these people
are driving somewhere.
Mm-hmm.
Capra, Jr. said
they bought the crane,
so they're gonna use it,
and here they go.
Now, everybody remember,
we're parking in the
turtle lot, the turtle lot.
"Hell Fighters" with
John Wayne will return.
( all humming )
It's George Bush.
Check it out.
Hey, look, they set up
a couple of wet bars.
It's Bolt versus Blaze
in an all-out battle,
tonight on
"American Gladiators!"
- Jump! Jump! Jump!
Jump!
This is Ground Control
to Major Tom.
You've really made the grade
and the papers want to know
whose shirts you wear.
Over.
( laughs )
Pull the GNN
circuit breakers and
the IMU heater breakers.
You do it.
I'm bitter.
Shut down the attitude
control system.
Oh, the attitude
control.
SCS secured.
Shut down number two
and three fuel cells.
We'll leave number one
on the line
in case we have to
charge the batteries.
Check and see
if I unplugged
the curling iron,
too, would you?
- What about the comm?
- No, we'll leave it on.
Flood lights off.
You guys
are great to be with.
Can we stay up
and talk a while?
- EL off.
- Yel-low.
Buzz, the lower
equipment bays dark?
Well, the B lights
are off.
Good night, Mrs. Calabash,
wherever you are.
And why isn't that off?
It's my nightlight.
I don't know why.
Gene, can I have
a drink of water?
Houston, Ironman,
we're cranked down.
Copy, Jim.
We'll check in
when you come over
the hill at Guaymas.
We're gonna keep you
informed every step
of the way.
Every movie you make,
every step you take,
we'll be watching you.
- In a while.
- Jim, this is Courtney.
Now, I want you to take
one tablet of Stryzene
after every meal.
- Who wants gum?
- I do! I do!
Complete the power down.
You can drink as much
water as you want.
Now, every word, every
emotion costs oxygen,
so the more relaxed
you are, the better.
All right, you bums, take
your pills and go to sleep.
Oh, jeez, he's drunk again.
Hey! Hello,
big brother.
- Hiya, Ted.
- Hiya, Stoney.
- Hey, where are you?
- I'm at Lucy's house.
Well, I'm in Huntsville,
kludging up a simulator
to the XRV.
I'm at Space Camp
with Kate Capshaw.
A simulator to the XRV.
I'm gonna do a little
brush up here
before I take it
to the Cape.
Well, this is a great time
to start learning
how to fly it.
Listen, all you guys
gotta worry about
is where you want me
to set you down
after I make
the transfer.
Go on, pick your spot.
Edwards? Vegas?
How about
the beach in Malibu?
Why not?
All right, take your
pills, go to sleep,
and leave
the driving to us.
Good night.
I'm out of here!
I'll see you in 39 hours
and 16 minutes.
Not if we see you first.
( laughs )
I love that one.
That's really good.
Tastes like fresh cherries.
I wonder what mine's
gonna taste like?
Mmm. ( gulps )
Gene, stop looking at it
and just eat it!
What's he doing?
He's crushing it into
his cleft on his chin.
A mortar and pestle.
Time to go.
Shoes for industry.
Shoes for the dead.
Hi, there. My name's
Joe Beats.
Say, what chance
does that--
Ironman One, Ironman One.
This is Houston.
Do you read me?
Roger that, Houston.
Coming in
on the wall-to-wall.
Roger that, Ironman.
Advise you adjust
your attitude
using happy hour
protocol 3-niner.
Roger that, 3-niner.
Houston, we're gonna
highball the Delta V
to modify attitude.
Roger, we have
cranked down on the IMU,
you-are-me, tuck
and roll formation.
Roger, Corman,
advise you pull all
GNN circuit breakers,
modify your ILM Skywalkers,
and full retraction
of your Robin Lame
Chartbusters
and hold on your power
and glory switches.
Roger on that
glory hold, sir.
Hold, I read Gypsy, doctor.
Serious start up leak
in apathy thrusters.
Serious yaw,
pitch and kick
with apathy flux and rate.
Roger. Stay calm, boys.
Shut down all SVS dissident
controls but number one.
Speaking of number one,
Stoney,
I got too much Tang in me.
I got renal overflow.
Better send up that
john, Houston.
Looks like Hackman here
has screwed the pooch.
Over.
Roger that, pooch.
We're cranked down
till 0-niner-fiver.
Check in when you come over
the hill at Cannery.
That's Canary, Crow.
Right, boys,
so just take your pills
and kiss
your apogee good-bye.
- What?
- What? What are you--
That's right,
this is Fugitive One.
When you want
headache relief fast,
two Bufferin
and a glass of scotch.
No, no! Joel!
He's wrecking everything.
- Crow, what are you doing?
- What are you doing there?
I'm just trying
to spice it up.
This here is The Fugitive
looking for
the riverboat queen,
hauling a load
of sailboat fuel
northbound on the nickel.
You got a bear
in your ear and a--
Crow! Crow, enough
with the CB lingo.
The only reason we did
this is because you
do such a killer Peck.
10-4, killer Peck.
You got some
rusty load running east
out of Needletown.
Looking at
the flabby gas passer,
I'll be 10-10
on the side of fries--
Joel: Come on.
You're coming with me
Crow: ♪ Riverboat queen,
coming in to Los Angeles ♪
♪ Bringing in
a couple of keys ♪
Open the pod bay door, Hal.
Whoa, movie sign!
- ( alarm )
- Help me. I'm stuck. Oh!
♪ Don't touch my bag
if you please ♪
Crow ruined everything.
I hate it when
you leave me hanging
in the middle
of skits like that.
I should caution you.
It's the beautiful
Breck girls.
You're gonna notice
some degeneration.
Is that good?
But it's important to show
them how confident you are.
We understand, Dick.
We won't let you down.
You want us
to be confident?
The more relaxed they are,
the less oxygen they use.
- I know why we're here.
- You do?
You're letting us
say good-bye.
Is that Lou Grant?
No, no, no. Lee Grant.
Lee Press-On Grant.
Celia?
Lee, honey, that's a Fall
if ever I saw one.
Jiggle the antenna.
Put it on channel 3.
Put some tin--
There you go.
- Hi, Celia.
- Hi, Frank.
Celia?
Oh! Nothing, nothing!
Wasn't touching.
It's okay.
Celia?
- Celia?
- You're breaking my heart.
Celia, we're gonna talk to him
on the monitor up here.
Okay.
What are you
laughing at?
You know, in those days,
you were required to smoke.
Honey, guess where
I'm calling from?
Celia.
Well, here I am again.
Signed, sealed, delivered,
I'm yours.
What are you wearing?
Everybody's so nice.
Sometime.
I spoke
to your father today.
- Uh-oh.
- And he says to say hello.
And he says he's sorry
you're going to die--
- I mean--
- Shh.
I bought some new shoes.
- Shoes. Huh.
- They hurt.
That's great.
What the heck does that
have to do with anything?
I'm dying up here!
- Kids?
- Fine, fine.
I lost the bill
to the insurance.
I thought I had it paid,
and then just this
morning, I got a letter.
Huh, I'd find that
and pay it
if I were you.
Listen, babe, I just want
to tell you that I love you.
What?
I said I love you.
In front of the guys?
I just wanted you
to know.
Mm-hmm, neat. Now, so
the house needs painting
and I was wondering if
you'd like a nice eggshell
or maybe an enamel?
I just wanted
to make sure.
Stoner, come on,
you're hurting my legs.
Scooch over.
Is it very lonely
where you are?
Nah, not with these guys.
Stoney's rigging
a beer bong.
No, I'm not.
Not for long.
We all have
great confidence.
That your death will be
quick and painless. Oops.
Celia, if you have,
you know,
any more problems
with the insurance
or the house
or anything like that,
you can talk to Dougherty.
- He's a good guy.
- And he's alive.
You can depend on him.
I gave him a kiss
to give you
when he sees you.
Just how many kisses
did you give him?
Just so when I see him,
I'll know.
Yeah, just what I need.
( laughs )
You never can tell.
A little tuned up, honey.
Uh-huh.
So I like pudding.
Well, I gotta go now.
- No, not yet.
- Where?
No, I mean, I really
have to go now.
Celia, I, uh...
I had a real good day today.
I made an ashtray.
And, you know, when you
think about this, uh...
And you will think about
this, please be kind.
I want you to remember
I had a real good day.
You're not giving me much
to work with, honey.
Jim...
( gulping )
We better cut it off now.
Will I see you in September
or lose you
to a summer love?
Oh, there's
one more thing.
I'm buying a--
well, I guess it can
wait until your dead--
I mean down. Sorry.
I lost five pounds
last week.
I can't wait
till you see me.
So? Big deal.
I'm weightless.
That tickles, honey.
Don't do that.
I'm too good,
in fact.
You take care of yourself.
Take care.
( sobbing )
And you're healed,
honey.
Note to myself,
remember the monitor thing
when he comes home.
I'm gonna be doing
TV movies
for the rest of my career.
( sobbing )
Celia, how'd it go
with Dick?
Does he know about us?
Could you touch
my screen, too?
Come on, Celia.
Hiya, sport.
Hiya, kid.
How are the mice?
Oh, they're dead.
How's the rabbit?
We're learning
something every day.
You writing a big
dull book up there?
No. I leave that
to James Michener.
Just a small, dull book.
How are you?
Gorgeous. And you?
I'm working on
a little project.
I've developed an
experimental hypothesis
for you to proof out.
Have you?
Well, what is it?
How long can you
hold your breath?
( whispering )
I miss you like mad.
Grrr. Yum, yum,
yum, yum.
Yeah, I love you,
too, honey.
Your paper
came out last week.
Oh, you got a B-.
Professor Stavel said it's
a brilliant presentation.
It was the best
he's ever read.
We're gonna make it,
Teresa.
- What?
- Huh?
We're gonna make it back.
- What?
- Huh?
We're going
to make it back.
Oh, that's great.
Now about the insurance.
I was wondering
if I have to--
- Believe me.
- Yes.
I'm mean it.
We're all coming back.
Back? Well...well...
could...when?
Could you call
first?
Listen, Teresa, I--
It's Teresa.
I want you
and the kids to--
Oh, wait, I've got
another call coming in.
Could you hold a minute? Uh.
Look, I have to go now.
I'll be seeing you.
Stoney.
- No, you hang up first.
- No, you hang up.
- No, you.
I love you.
Remember that.
What was
the middle part?
Remember that.
We'll always have
Encino. Whatever.
Oh, fudge,
he was my connection.
( blubbering )
This makes for great TV.
Buzz?
Ah, what? Nothing.
I wasn't doing...just...
General LeClair
called all the way
from Clark's Field.
He asked me to dinner.
I thought
that was so nice.
Oh, and Jim Garner
called, too.
They want to
give you something.
A headstone.
Look, hon, you don't
seem to understand.
It's all falling apart
up here. You understand?
Well, that's nice, honey.
I understand, Buzz.
You see, I broke
the washing machine,
and now I can't fix it.
What is he, the Maytag
repairman all of a sudden?
I understand
how you feel.
I could fix it if they'd
give me the tools,
but they won't.
Listen, honey,
I wrote something.
It's called
"The Reluctant Astronaut
Bites the Big One."
- Do you want to hear it?
- What?
The President,
the White House,
Washington D.C.
Dear Mr. President,
We just wanted
to let you know...
She's making this up.
How much we appreciate
the heroic actions
to save our husbands.
We are grateful to you
and to everyone
in the nation.
The team effort
of the past two days
will be an inspiration
to us, our children...
God, this is so
poorly written. Jeez.
Don't you understand?
It's all falling apart
and they're blaming me
and I don't feel very good.
Can I fix you a nice 7-Up
and soda crackers, dear?
Buzz...
I have to go now.
Bye.
I love you.
I'll see you later.
Bye, honey. Guy's
a five-pound fruitcake.
I gotta get out of here.
The other husbands
were so strong
and mine's
a tower of Jell-O,
but he's good, though.
Hmm.
Sorry, everyone, sorry.
Oh, turn him off.
Buzz, can you give me
a reading
on your partial pressure
of carbon dioxide?
- ( inhales ) Here.
- Thank you very much.
I just gave you that!
Turn it off!
- Negative, Buzz.
- Turn it off!
Negative.
You gave me a PS--
This is good TV.
What's going on
down there?
Why don't you get us
out of here?
Get a hold of him, Jim.
Get him away
from the controls!
Why don't you come up here
and get us out of here?
Sedate him.
Put on some Dan Fogelberg.
Buzz? Come on.
- Buzz.
- Oh, no.
He thinks he's Shatner,
for crying out loud.
Now just get us out of here,
that's all! Come on!
- Buzz off.
- I'll say.
That's my man
up there.
You better have a woman's
lounge around here.
I've got points
on this game.
I can't believe
you bet on the Bears.
It is cold out there.
T-minus 60 seconds
and counting.
- Hold!
I'm gonna do
what Greg does.
Shut her down.
Damn.
Tower crew to launch pad.
Move in, Tower.
But for Vince Lombardi
and the Green Bay Packers,
there would come
another day.
Gene? Gene, buddy,
chin up.
Hey.
Oh, man.
Houston, Ironman,
do you read?
I can't read.
That's my secret shame.
Goldstone, this is Ironman.
Do you read?
Goldstone,
this is Kidney Stone,
gallstone niner.
I know you're there.
Stop screening your calls.
Guaymas, Ironman.
Rubber ply,
this is Iron John.
Gene, what does your suit
smell like, buddy? ( laughs )
Cape, this is Ironman.
Pruett?
I'm sorry, I thought Jim
was gonna get it
and he thought
I was gonna get it.
I'm sorry. We had
to scrub the launch.
Hey, hey, hey,
there's ladies present.
These guys better
scrub the inside
of their suits.
Yeah.
Yeah, I figured
it might be like that.
We've been
watching the storm.
We suggest you start
breathing in shifts.
T-minus 60 seconds.
Now, listen, Jim,
we're still working
on that engine.
Oh, you got the engine
down there?
No wonder it doesn't work.
Oh, great. Now
there's a bank robbery.
Oh, this bites,
Houston. Over.
Boss, I just...
I wanted to tell you
that you've done
a great job.
Well, up till now
at any rate.
And, uh...
Well, no hard feelings.
The place looks great
and you look great
and, well, you know.
I just want to say...
♪ I'm so glad we had
this time together ♪
Now you've done
a great job, really.
I'd like to be fed
to my dog.
It's nobody's fault.
Good night now.
GBI reports loss of signal.
Ascension will acquire
the spacecraft.
Shall we remote
you through?
No.
Move in, white room.
Get the pilot out of there.
It's Storming Norman.
Check it out.
Now get me Keith.
I want to speak to Keith.
Talk to me,
sweetcakes.
We've done everything
we possibly could.
We cannot launch.
But I'm telling you
to launch!
You get this hay wagon
off the ground!
No, no,
I can't hear you.
I'm can't--
I'm leaving.
La-la-la-la.
I do not hear you.
Okay. Stay
with the group.
We promise you'll see
some stars this tour.
In one of these buildings,
there may be a hurricane.
Look, there's
Gregory Peck.
- Wow, whoo!
- ( applauding )
Here he comes.
( humming theme to
"The Dick Van Dyke Show" )
All right, shoot.
But first,
a few bird calls.
I have a brief statement.
The launch
of the XRV rescue craft
was scrubbed
at 8:47 Cape time.
The pad was shut down
at T-minus 58 seconds.
Last call was at 1:45.
When the wind velocity
in the launch area
rose to 48 knots.
And tiny sandwiches
are being put back
in deep freeze.
Commander Pruett in
the Apollo Command Module
has been informed.
He wept openly
like a little baby.
This...
Is this.
This was a very fine,
fine effort.
- Looks good.
- Do you have any questions?
Mr. Keith,
you say that--
Is there any way
I can look any dorkier?
Does that mean you're
going to reschedule
at a later time?
No, we have no plans.
Will there be any
future rescue attempts?
We have no plans.
Oh, no, that guy
was in Rocket Club,
definitely.
Mr. Keith, you say
the men have been informed.
Who informed them?
I did.
What was their reaction?
They liked it,
liked it a lot.
Do you have
any other questions?
I have a quote
from Mr. Hackman.
He said, "Aah!"
There's a general
assumption
that the space program
will be brought
to a halt
for an investigation
of the accident.
Check out Pee-Wee's
evil brother on the right.
Plus a general
examination
of our purposes in space
and the morality
of putting men
into space without
adequate--
What's your question?
Why is Richard Speck
looking over my shoulder
is my question?
Are the results you gained
worth the lives you lost?
You're damn right they are!
You wanna know what
they accomplished
living up there in
a tin can for five months?
Well, lots of stuff.
Because of men like these,
we've taken the first step
off this little planet.
The trip to the moon
was just a walk
around the block.
We're going to the stars.
Your little
small town pissant.
To other worlds,
other civilizations.
Mr. Keith?
I want this man
savagely beaten.
Men will be killed
in this effort,
just as they're killed
in cars and airplanes,
in bars and in bed.
What is it?
Are you sure you want
to say that?
- Look at the numbers.
- What about them?
The numbers, Mr. Keith,
the numbers.
What numbers?
Let me see.
In God's name.
I just won lotto.
I quit! Whoo!
( all shouting )
Well, these are some pics
that my kids drew.
Yeah, I hope
you like them.
Who cut out the ad?
I haven't even read
this yet.
We have 90-knot winds.
In the center or eye,
we have zero.
Oh, oh, Mr. Liddy?
Mr. Liddy?
It's over the Cape.
All I wish to hear
from each of you
is yes or no, go or no go.
Uh, go.
We have a launch window
while the eye
is over the Cape.
We affirm a launch window
at 22:31:06.
Can you launch your rocket
through the eye
of the hurricane?
- Yes, sir.
- If I felt like it.
Will the bird fly?
Well, it's been kicked
around by 80-knot winds.
- The data's a little--
- What's your judgment?
It'll fly.
- Carp?
- Yes, sir.
Carp?
Do we have 16 minutes
in the eye?
No, sir, not 16.
Do we have 14?
Well, we've been trying
to get a prog chart--
Come on, Carp,
yes or no!
What's your judgment?
I'll buy 14.
Can we move the tower
back in 12 minutes?
You give the order
and we'll do it.
Houston, Flight.
That's your night
retainer, sir.
Is the rescue craft
go for Port Charlie?
We can have
Point Charlie, yes,
but from there on in,
the pilot
will be on his own.
Rescue, can you rendezvous
without an onboard
computer program?
You just get me
in the ballpark.
As long as it's not
in the Metrodome.
Then we are go for launch
at 22:31:06 local time.
Just deal with it,
Carp.
22:31:06 local time.
Roger. 2-2-3-1-0-6
local time.
Give or take an hour.
We'll recycle
to T-minus 30.
That's Peter
Ueberroth there.
When this is over, let's
find a quiet spot, huh?
By 22:31:06,
the crew will be dead.
There's not enough
oxygen left
for three men
to live that long.
What about two men?
What about
six midgets?
We plot total pressure
against total use.
Is there sufficient oxygen
for two men?
What about two men
standing on each
others shoulders?
Or one?
How about two small
dogs and a bat?
A porcupine, perhaps?
Two might just make it.
Two small dogs
it is then.
Hey, someone left
the Cape out in the rain.
- Oh, yeah.
- I had to do it.
I do love
The Weather Channel.
It's good.
It really is good.
Now for this word
from Dial. ( laughs )
- I did it again.
- Stop it, you.
Sorry.
Gee, just trying to get
the BB in the bear's eye.
I love these
pocket puzzles.
Almost, yeah.
- Oh!
- Move back service tower.
( wind blows )
♪ We're out of the dark,
we're out of the woods ♪
♪ We're out of the night ♪
This is launch control.
We have just confirmed
that all spacecraft
systems are go
at this time.
Launch director
is about to feed
the final computer update
to the spacecraft.
Wow, check out all
the night crawlers!
This is
an unbelievable scene.
No wind.
Absolute silence.
Overhead, nothing but black
night and brilliant stars.
He's talking into
a Fudgsicle.
As the eye
of the Hurricane Alma
passes directly over us.
You say the magic word
and you get a $100.
There's an eerie hush
over everything here.
♪ All over the world ♪
No rain, no wind.
The lives of three men
are measured by
their fading heartbeats
and here on pad 41
at Cape Kennedy,
we're right in the middle
of another heartbeat.
It's a single moment
in the life of a great storm.
Vinyl seat covers
on the cameras.
How tacky.
A reprieve, we hope,
for Pruett, Lloyd and Stone.
The service tower is rolling
away from the launch pad.
( gasps )
Somebody stop it!
As soon as
it's 800 feet away,
it'll be locked
into position,
but they'll launch
before that happens.
That tower is expendable,
but the three men--
Are slightly less
expendable than
that tower.
Ironman One, Houston CapCom,
do you read?
Hey, isn't the machine
supposed to kick in
after four rings?
Ironman One, this is Houston
Flight, do you read me?
You want to trade seats
or something?
Ironman, this is Keith.
What the hell
do they want?
Flint. Flint!
Ugh, I'm up, I'm up.
What, what?
Hello, Jim, I want
to talk to you.
Yeah, what do you want?
I have some
numbers for you.
The eye of the hurricane
passed over the Cape
at 22:18,
and we had a second window
at 22:31:06 Cape time.
Now, I want you to add
those numbers.
I want to check out
the John Ritter
learning system.
We've successfully
launched the rescue craft
through the eye,
do you understand?
You have launched
the XRV?
Yes, that's correct.
The XRV has completed staging.
It's a Honda,
actually, a CRX.
It's only a two-seater,
so one of you has to go.
Our transfer
will be at 23:28.
That's 55 minutes
from now. Do you read?
Right, right. We'll
take a vote on it,
but we're kind of getting
used to the idea of death.
I told Stoney I loved him.
Jim, how do you, uh...
How do you evaluate
the oxygen situation?
What oxygen? ( laughs )
I kid. I'm just a cut-up.
Well, we have
whatever oxygen is left
in the spacecraft system.
And then there's
whatever's in the air.
Two bottles
of emergency oxygen on
board, five minutes each.
That's 10 man-minutes.
We can always squeeze
Stoner for a quart.
My backpack and Lloyd's
and Stone's...
Burp a little.
But there's not much
oxygen left in them.
Well, you'll have to
save your backpacks
for the EVA transfer.
- Yeah, I know that.
- Duh.
55 minutes.
Stoney's shrooming.
Look at him.
We'll be dead by then.
Well, that's how
I see it, too.
Looks like we solved
this problem. Thanks.
Continue to use oxygen
at the present rate.
Well, we can't cut down.
Let's think about that.
Won't you?
Thank you.
You want us to lower the
partial pressure again?
No, we've examined that.
It won't work.
Should we all beat around
the bush a little more?
Well, we're lying here
like corpses now.
What else can we do?
I'm glad
you brought that up.
Now you've got it.
You must think.
Duh, one, duh, two.
The guy in the middle,
he's the trouble-maker.
You know it.
Yeah,
we're thinking.
L-tay, only-stay,
m-scray.
Are we talking about
the same thing?
Are you talking to me?
Yeah.
Why don't you
talk it over?
If you could
work out something,
it would be
a great help.
Yeah, we'll
talk it over.
I must point out, Jim,
that any effective action
must be taken immediately.
Look, don't tell me
what to do!
We've been taking your
goddamn orders
and where the hell
are we?
From now on, we're gonna
make all the decisions!
Dirty anarchist.
Whatever we do,
you're out of it!
Oh, I appreciate
what you're saying, Jim,
and I agree with you.
You're exactly right.
You are correct, sir.
( clears throat )
Yeah, anything else?
Yes, to two of you,
good luck.
To one of you,
good-bye.
Would you please give me
those launch numbers
again?
Yes, that's launch
at 22:31:06 Cape time.
Rendezvous
and transfer at 23:28.
And breakfast
any ol' time.
Thanks.
For nothing.
( laughs ) Wait till they
find out I'm joking.
There's plenty of air
for everyone. ( laughs )
You know, they say someday
these will be cordless.
Launch at 22:31:06.
Rendezvous 23:28.
He's a pretty funny guy,
isn't he?
55 minutes to go.
Counting commercials?
Through the eye
of a hurricane.
Quit breathing so hard.
Jesus, 55 minutes.
Well, Stoney, you still
have that pillow?
Right. It'll be
pretty cold by then.
You know, when you put
your mouth down here,
you can make a funny noise.
Well, one of us
is gonna have to go.
I mean, uh...
I just went.
That's what we're talking
about, isn't it?
One of us goes
and the other two stay?
Well, I think it should be
old Zeppelin lungs Hackman.
I'll stay.
I want to be the one.
You're closest
to the door.
- I could move.
- What are we gonna do?
♪ Should I stay
or should I go? ♪
All right, let's
do it scientifically.
Two big guys throw
the little guy out, okay?
- ( all laugh )
- That's a good idea.
Um, well--
I wasn't joking, Gene.
Serves you right
for doing "Gypsy Moths."
Well, we're gonna have
to talk about this.
So what are we gonna do?
We already told you.
Throw you out.
Think we're joking?
Are we amusing you?
Do you think
we're clowns?
I could do it by chance.
I'll tear out
strips from a pad.
One short, two long.
The guy
with the short end goes.
Well, they could
flip a coin,
but it would never
come down.
They could play Yahtzee.
Play Yahtzee. Yeah.
Tear the little guy
in half.
Well, look, I don't want
to just lay here and die.
I want to shake the dirt
of this crumby capsule
off my shoes
and see the world.
Two guys, three guys,
is that much difference?
I say double the pills.
Put ourselves out.
Wait, are there five
all of a sudden?
Did I miss something?
Even when there's
no pressure,
there's still oxygen
molecules floating around.
You live for a while
even when there's no
pressure in the gauges.
Yeah, my cousin
did it once.
For God's sake,
it's less than 55 minutes!
- You're dreaming, Stone.
- All right. Okay.
- I'll go.
- Good.
Wait, I'm locked in.
I can't. I'm sorry.
I'm the weakest. I'm
using up the most oxygen.
I'll go. It's all right.
All right, all right.
It really isn't what you call
a win-win situation, is it?
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
All right,
get your helmets on.
I'm going out
to fix the engine.
Are you kidding? You
can't fix that engine.
Oh, who died and made you
President of the capsule?
There.
I don't know why I let
them talk me out of it.
I should've done this
two days ago.
Come on,
get your helmets on.
Hey, look,
it's a big old '59 Caddy
with a carbuncle on the back.
Anyone seen
my Grecian formula?
I left it here,
a small bottle,
says "Greg."
I think I'll play
a little Super Mario,
if you don't mind.
Okay. Don't everyone
talk at once.
Well, now, that was
a riveting scene, wasn't it?
- ( Crow whistle )
- Yeah.
Breathe deep
the gathering gloom.
Richard, unh-unh.
Don't touch that.
Unh-unh, no.
Hey, that's
the yogurt machine.
Don't you dare
go out there.
I don't want you
out there.
Well, while
he's going out,
let's us go out, huh?
Mm, let's us go out.
- Take a cue.
- Well said.
Hey, there's lots
of oxygen out there.
Hey, did you guys ever think
about what might happen
if one of us would
have to leave the ship
in order to save
the others?
- Uh, nope.
- Not really, no.
Really?
Not in the least?
Can't say as I have,
Skipper.
Yeah, pretty cut and dried
if you think about it.
Oh, come on,
you guys are saying
that this film hasn't
touched you in the least?
Three men
marooned in space.
You know, they're
addressing a problem
that we someday
may have to face.
And, you know, who can put
a value on human life?
I mean, who can decide
who lives and who dies?
I do, remember?
I called dibs.
Joel, I hate to be
the shriveled carrot
under your
peach cobbler, but--
Yeah, Joel, there really
isn't anything to talk about.
- You're a human.
- You need oxygen to breathe.
We don't.
We're robots.
Exceptionally cute
robots, I think.
Yes, exactly.
Oh, and clever, too.
I was gonna say
irreverent and witty.
- Droll, yet insightful.
- Oh, hardly different.
I'm already alone,
aren't I?
He'll fix it.
Oh. Hey, guys.
You're a big help.
He'll fix it.
You son of a bitch.
You know what
he's doing up there.
He's smoking.
Buzz, don't!
He told me he was
out of cigarettes.
Jim! Get back in here.
Jim, don't do it!
Okay, now where's the hood
on this goofy thing?
You're going to rip
out the umbilicals.
Jim, don't do it! Jim!
Jim!
I'm hiding down here.
Jim, don't do it! Jim!
Jim, come back in here
and put your mittens on!
No, Jim, don't.
Really, no, don't go.
Stoney? Stoney, give me
some line here. Stoney?
Feed me, Jack,
feed me!
Well, what do you know?
( laughs )
Jim, quick,
throw us your Rolex!
You know he's gonna
burst like a balloon.
It's sad really.
Mm. If you
think about it.
Doggone it, Jim,
you got the keys!
I'm melting...melting.
Oh, he cubed it, man.
I don't think
I can watch this. No way.
Dying is easy.
Comedy is hard.
Oh, so Richard Crenna
said that?
Yep, think so.
Either that matte
painting goes or I do.
Oh, he said that, too?
Wait, one last bit.
Like my Cagney?
You dirty rat...
Luke! Lukey, dagnabbit!
You get back
in this ship right now
before I tan your hide.
Hey, you didn't sign
our yearbook.
Hey, it's Matt Dillon
and Penny Marshall.
♪ I'd rather be a hammer
than a snail ♪
Huh? Oh.
Yeah, he's dead.
Can we still
have dinner?
Is that a no?
Well, you think
about it.
Tonight, the music
of Laserium.
Uh, Carl would
like to see you.
Haunting, isn't it?
Alan Sheppard in
a well-received cameo.
Oh, he must share an office
with Fred McMurray.
Major Healy here
will be right in.
Get out! Get out!
The calls are coming
from inside NASA!
If you have a husband
in space, press one.
If you have a dead
husband in space,
press two.
Mrs. Pruett, I wanted
to talk to you.
I'm calling from
your credit union.
Your husband is dead.
- And how are you?
- Way to let her down easy.
It was an accident.
We were playing
and, well, mommy said
I was too rough.
He was trying to repair
the spacecraft.
And he shot himself.
So I was wondering
if you'd like to have
some dinner.
You like Chinese?
I know this place.
It's called The Crash Pad.
So how are things
on your end?
Not so good, huh?
Well, my condolences.
I'm sending you
a case of steaks.
Hello? Really?
Please, let a smile
be your umbrella.
I speak from the--
Yay! It's not us!
Whoo! Whoo!
( whistles )
Now we got some room.
Thought he'd never leave.
Scooch over.
- Excuse me.
- I told you, Jim's not here.
He had an accident.
Dave's not here, man.
Where's Stoney at?
I'm here.
Stoney?
Dougherty's coming.
Man, they're really cutting
loose on that breathing thing
now that that guy's gone.
Yeah, they're breathing
for two now.
Stoney, tell Jim...
I love him.
To get us out of here.
Stop eating your oxygen,
damn you! Be still!
- It's Chuck Heston.
- Sounded like him.
Oh, look, the mothership.
The funkadelic
mothership?
- Range 76.8.
- Mm-hmm.
And since when did NASA
paint anything red?
I'm a little
under the line.
Rescue, Flight.
Janssen under the line?
Right.
Roger, attitude is go,
Delta V 63.
You know, either that ship
is tiny or he's huge.
Roger, 3, 2, 1.
Oh, that helped.
Watch this.
Oxygen.
- Can't.
- Nope.
Can't. Gotta save it
for the transfer.
No, not another bite
until we get to Grandma's.
I got a big scene coming up.
I need the oxygen.
Oh.
Oh, you're not dying.
I'm dying. Great.
It takes a long time to die.
Ironman, this is Rescue.
Read you.
Read you? I love you.
Turn on your
acquisition lights.
Say again?
Come on, Stoney, turn on
your acquisition lights.
Turn on
your love light!
- Roger.
- And leave it on.
Roger. Acquisition lights.
Boy, are those bright.
Pretty bright lights.
Okay, Stoney, I'm coming
right down the pipe.
I'll see you
in six minutes.
Wow, you thought of me,
man. All right.
- Six minutes.
- Roger.
Buzz, six more minutes.
Phooey, phooey, phooey,
phooey, phooey on the ship.
Phooey on the ship
is what I say.
Can't...
You can, buddy.
You've got to!
Hey, everybody, it's
the Stoney and Buzz show.
Think of something nice.
Think, uh...
That Buzz has been
a raspberry seed in my
wisdom tooth long enough.
Think of the Earth, Buzz.
Look at the Earth, Buzz.
Look, can you tell
where we are?
Over the dells?
Stoney?
I'm right here, okay?
All right, Buzz.
All right.
You can sit
next to the window.
All right.
Time for that Flowbee
haircut. Come on.
All of you.
Okay, open wide.
Here comes papa.
Oh.
All right, Buzz,
you're on my air now.
Oh...oh, that's good.
Oh, my God,
what the heck are they
doing up there?
Cabin air. There
must be some left.
Hey, that's not half bad.
- Smells fresh.
- Hmm.
Oh, finally,
the cable guy's here.
- Took him long enough.
- The Russian cable guy.
Huh?
♪ In our Easter bonnets ♪
♪ With all the red,
black around it ♪
( laughs )
Who's laughing?
I can't figure it out.
Oh, the other Gene
is laughing.
Oh, Gene, I hooked you
into the nitrous.
- I'm sorry.
- ( laughs )
( rapid beeping )
Come here, you.
Tuck in that shirt.
You look ridiculous with
the tails hanging out.
( laughs )
That's enough
for you, dude.
Oh, roger. Dave, we
don't need you anymore.
The Russians rescued
them. Thanks anyway.
Roger, Ted, you've got
their acq lights.
( laughs )
Whoo-hoo, that's a good one.
That was number nine.
Whoo-hoo-hoo.
I kill me.
Blow the hatch.
Do not!
Do not blow the hatch!
( laughs ) Bite me.
I'm blowing the hatch.
Whoo-hoo. Oh, look.
We're heating the outside now.
Damn them!
Damn them all to hell!
( laughs )
All right, chuckles,
up you go. Come on.
♪ There's a bright
golden haze on the meadow ♪
Hey, is that Nancy Sinatra?
No, that was Servo.
The boots. He's
talking about the boots.
Oh. ( laughs ) Okay.
Never told you this before.
Gene's got nice legs,
doesn't he?
All right,
where's the supernova?
Pull it over. Come on.
He can't get
any closer, Buzz.
If I was any closer,
I'd be behind you.
Whoa, I've been shooting
red and yellows all day.
I'm so sleepy.
There's the pitch.
Come here, dumbsky.
Oh, looks like
it's low and away.
It's gonna be ball one.
Oops, I don't got you.
I meant to do that.
Oh, so sorry,
Mr. American Space Guy.
Oops. Bye-bye.
Well, we lost
another one in the sun.
You know, I thought
Walter was gonna really
do it this year,
but, well, anyway,
it's a good time right now
for an ice cold
Budweiser beer.
I'm just gonna lie down
for a little catnap.
Just a little
winky dinky.
( snoring )
And now, ladies
and gentlemen,
the mystery of the
astral levitation.
He's got a nice
vacuum-sealed codpiece
on there.
I mean, look at that.
I'll get you.
I'm not that drunk.
Had to stop off
at a package store.
Would have been here sooner,
but I hit all the lights.
I've got visual
on them now.
I'm gonna
break down to 10.
They're about 50 feet apart.
The Apollo hatch is open.
Can you see the crew?
I'm gonna break down
and cry.
Negative.
I'm gonna go in
a little closer.
Oop. I just
fried 'em. Sorry.
♪ Low riders in the sky ♪
Turn your blinker off.
Dude, pretty hot
spaceship.
Now there's a light flashing
from the Russian ship.
Hey, you kids, get going.
Get a move on. Come on.
Hey, Ivan, got any vodka
in there? I'm dying.
Some guy floating
about a 150 feet below me.
I'm going after him.
My guess would be it's
the guy you're looking for.
Neat. Major Matt Mason.
Sure wish I had me
one of those jetpacks.
♪ Be a perfect sleeper,
be a perfect sleeper ♪
♪ Perfect sleeper
by Serta ♪
- Shall we have it?
- Mm-hmm.
No, no, made a mistake.
It's not him.
It's somebody else.
I don't know who.
Never pick up hitchhikers.
Unh-uh.
All right, come to me,
my sweet friend. Come on.
Come to papa.
Oh, hi.
I feel like a dope.
Sorry you had to
come out all this way.
Eh, no problem.
I'm just gonna have
to take your appendix.
Don't mind me.
My appendix?
Hey, look, he's got a
super squirter in there.
Oh, no, that's a little
baby nitrous thing there.
Ooh. ( giggles )
Gee, thanks,
I guess. Huh?
Well, then.
Hey, hey, hey,
wait a minute.
I was just about to
become a star child.
There's nothing
going on out here.
I'm going back in.
Hey, hey, look, I found
another one out here.
They're everywhere
and they're free. ( laughs )
I know it's kind of ugly.
Just get in.
I kind of live
out of my satellite.
We'll get your head
all polished up.
Get a nice meal.
Oh, hey,
look at that thing.
You can see the strings.
Fakey, fakey.
Yeah, it's really fake.
And look, you can see
their backpacks, too.
- Yeah--huh?
- Oh, yeah.
Excuse me, sir.
Would you step out
of the vehicle please?
May I see your license
and identification?
Mom, is that you?
You know,
the ironic thing
is that in real life,
James Franciscus died
and Richard Crenna
was still alive.
And he was "The Finder
of Lost Loves."
No, that's Tony Franciosa.
Think about it.
Oh.
- Baby Jessica?
- Come in, Ironman.
I feel like
some pineapple
upside down cake.
Okay, who am I now?
Mussolini, right?
Yeah, thank you
very much. Thank you.
Uh-oh.
Stoner cubed it.
Ironman, this is Keith.
Come in.
Hey, hey, hey,
he's touching him
in the space suit area.
Bad touch. Bad touch.
Hey, that's my wallet.
He's rolling me.
Yeah, sometimes
I like to sit out here
and just look at
the stars and think.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
I haven't had a single
good scene yet.
Please watch for me
in "MacKenna's Gold"
and the "Omen."
( hums theme from
"MacKenna's Gold" )
Ironman One, this is Keith.
Do you read me?
You know, he even looks
like a Russian, doesn't he?
I smell a rat,
a big commie rat.
Ooh, shh.
Just take a look.
Isn't he cute
when he's asleep?
Hold on. He only takes
unleaded, Mr. Russia.
I would've done that,
but our hoses
are not compatible.
Yeah, yeah.
Huh?
( groans )
"Longstreet."
I'm on "Longstreet."
Packs, sit packs.
( groans )
You know
I was skeptical,
but I like you guys.
It's fun.
Ironman, do you read me?
Cape, this is Rescue.
I'm in the Apollo.
The Russian
got some air to Stoney
and I've transferred him
to my oxygen.
His head looks like
a gumball machine.
Stupid guy's
stranded in space,
head looks like
a gumball machine.
- And I've got Lloyd.
- ( cheering )
Hey, we're getting color
TVs, everybody. Whoo-hoo!
A wrap party
right after strike.
They're really immature,
aren't they?
( cheering )
Thank you.
Don't touch me.
I'm not really
a party person.
( cheering )
- Whoo!
- Look out. He's crazy.
Mama. Mama.
We know. Sure.
Whatever you say.
Yeah, right.
Uh-huh. Neat.
♪ Riding the storm out ♪
( imitates drums )
♪ Waiting for... ♪
Prepare
for re-entry.
Roger. Prepare
Yeah, what a day.
Yeah, Ralph,
I'm gonna take off.
You guys lock up.
I've got my keys.
Well, got to go.
Got a date with
a very special widow.
Lee Grant,
a very lucky lady.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Gregory Peck,
ladies and gentlemen.
Gregory Peck.
Let's bring him out again.
How about it?
10, 9, 8, 7...
♪ 'Cause they're technicians,
identical technicians ♪
- 4, 3, 2, 1.
- Pilot light.
Whoo!
Roasting.
- Okay, Chuck.
- Good-bye.
- Bye.
- I had a nice time.
You know the Russians
based their spaceship
on Scrubbing Bubbles.
They do all the work
so you don't have to.
Nanu, nanu. This is--
Oh, look,
it got all loggy
and they left
the door open.
This is Mork
calling Orson.
Mork calling Orson.
That was a wonderful,
powerful ending.
I love this music.
♪ Like a circle
in a spiral ♪
♪ Like a wheel
within a wheel ♪
♪ Never ending-- ♪ Whoa.
Play the video game.
Read the Bantam book.
Soundtrack available
on RSO Records,
or hit the demo button
on any Casio keyboard.
I think it's time
to roll. Whoo.
I'm John Palmer and this
is the "NBC Nightly News."
- Total fake out.
- Works every time.
Hey, do you guys like
having fun with magic?
Oh, sure,
we love having fun,
and we like
to be with others.
What we know
about others,
which isn't much,
considering we've
spent our lives
locked in space
with you.
Now what about this
trick here, Le Pétomane?
I like dynamically
changing people's lives
through humorous skits
and stories, Joel,
and I'm not just saying
that to be a kiss-up.
Thanks, little-itty buddy.
Anyway, what we got here
is a trick
that involves
these scale models
of the control module.
- Cool.
- And these little
James Franciscus
action figures, okay?
- Put that in there like that.
- Stoney.
Okay, now, what I'm gonna do
is take--find the--
it's called find the
"Finder of Lost Loves," okay?
And so I mix them here.
Joel, Joel,
I don't want to wreck
your routine here,
but the "Finder
of Lost Loves"
was Tony Franciosa.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Well, where is the James
Franciscus action figure?
Well, it's simple.
It's right there,
right where you put it.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
I'm afraid that's the Tony
Franciosa action figure.
Find the "Finder
of Lost Loves."
I know, okay.
Okay, there it is.
- Hello, it was fun.
- I know.
Okay, okay,
which one--where's the--
where's the James
Franciscus action figure?
On the left.
Definitely on the left.
- Okay.
- I'm not wearing
my underwear.
- No, I'm sorry.
- Oh.
That's the Ben Gazzara
action figure.
It's fun to be fooled.
Okay, finally.
Okay, I'll buy
Fruit Stripes gum.
Turn over
the middle one.
No, I'm sorry,
that one contains
the James Farentino
action figure,
the Joseph Campanella
and the Burl Ives
action figure.
- The bald ones!
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, stung again!
All right, anyway,
now let's do a few letters,
you guys, okay?
This first one--
put that up on still, sirs--
from David St. Albins.
He's from Albuquerque,
New Mexico.
Albu-quirky.
"This is on camera
granted," he says.
So that's good.
Anyway, it says,
"Move over, pink boys.
There's a new gang
in town."
And it's got us in clothes.
- Nice drawing.
- Yeah, it's good.
They never quite
capture you though,
do they?
- No. Well, he's close.
- It's not bad.
And then this one.
Here's this little
photo collage they gave us.
- Oh, now, that's neat.
- And that's pretty good.
And that comes from
Matthew Fisher, who's 14,
and then Matthew Fiddler
his friend,
who's also 15.
- Matt and Matt.
- And he writes,
"P.P.S.: Who designed
Crow and Tom Servo?"
- That would be me.
- You did?
"P.P.S.: My friend and I
would like to see more
of Cambot on the show."
That's impossible.
- He's right over there.
- Buddy.
Hi, Cambot. And finally,
"P.P.P.S. where did you get
Mexican stoplight candy?"
The answer to that
is Mexico.
- Mexico.
- That's right.
Oh, my goodness.
- Hey!
- My ping pong balls!
She's gagging. Quick!
Whoo-ooh-ooh.
What do you think, sirs?
- Ahh!
- Ahh.
Push the button,
Frank.
Yeah.